Guide to the Levy Dime Novel Collection 1821-1968 Levy
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
Levy Dime Novel Collection
1780-1968
Levy
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
161.0 linear feet (161 boxes)
The Levy Dime Novel Collection contains mainly late 19th and early 20th Century fiction, in the form of cheap paperback novels and periodicals. Part of the collection is focused on what Levy referred to as "feminine" fiction: works about, authored by, and intended for women.
Provenance
Edward G. Levy made his first deposit of materials to the Fales Library in December 1964 with the idea of establishing a representative collection of nineteenth-century popular fiction at NYU. Larger shipments followed between May of 1965 and August of 1967. In November of 1969 Mr. Levy formally donated all previous deposits to the Fales Library. He also presented additional items at this time to bring the total number of items up to 8,427. Further gifts arrived in August 1973, November 1974, and September 1975 adding approximately 8,400 items for a total of nearly 17,000 items.
Itemized checklists exist for most of the gifts received by the library, some prepared by Mr. Levy prior to shipment and some by the Fales staff upon receipt. An unknown number of items were integrated into the Fales American and British collections and some items were sent to the circulating collection but no documentation of these transfers exists.
In the mid-1990s the Levy materials were packed into archival folders and boxes for storage and a box-level checklist was created. In 2003-2004 this item-level finding aid was created without further physical reorganization of the materials.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers without restrictions. Appointments are necessary to consult archive and manuscript collections.
Biographical Note
Edward G. Levy was born in New Haven, Connecticut on October 21, 1898. In 1939, he began seriously collecting 19th Century literary materials. During this time, he co-founded the Charlton Publishing Corporation, which he later sold in order to catalogue his 150,000 books, manuscripts, and memorabilia. Levy established collections with these materials at over a dozen institutions, including the Fales Library, where he built a significant collection through multiple donations. The New York Public Library, the Beinecke Library at Yale, and the Rappaporte Library at Brandeis also received substantial gifts from Mr. Levy.
Scope and Content Note
The Levy Dime Novel Collection contains a wide range of novels, periodicals, and serials dating from as early as 1780 through 1968. The bulk of the material dates from the 1880's and 90's. One of the areas of focus is on what Levy called "feminine" fiction: works composed by, about, and/or for women. Complete sets of The Merriwell Library by Burt L. Standish, The Pirate Story Series, and The Deadwood Dick Library by Edward L. Wheeler are included in the collection. Among the authors well represented are Miss. M. E. Braddon, Charlotte M. Brame/Bertha M. Clay, Nicholas Carter, The Duchess, Charles Garvice, Mrs. Mary J. Holmes, Old Sleuth, and Mrs. Emma D. E. N. Southworth.
Arrangement
The items were processed in the order in which they were boxed for offsite storage, being divided into novels, periodicals, miscellaneous addenda, flats, and oversize materials. Each of these categories is in near alphabetical order according to author's name or, for periodicals, publication name. There is no box #57, #84, #96, #104, #119, #123, or #138.
Series I: Novels (Box 1-83)
Series II: Monographic Series (Box 85-91)
Series III: Periodicals (Box 92-122)
Series IV: Bound Novels
Series V: Misc. Addenda
Series VI: Flat Boxes
Series VII: Oversize
Series VIII: Facsimile Reprints
Series IX: Miscellany
Related Material at Fales Library and Special Collections
Ralph Adimari Papers William J. Benners Papers
Separated Material
Dale, Alan. A Marriage Below Zero. New York: G. W. Dillingham, 1889. was removed and catalogued in Special Collections and is listed in Bobcat.
Beadle and Adams (1872-1898).; F.M. Lupton (Firm).; George Munro (Firm).; George Munro's Sons.; Harper & Brothers.; James Henderson (Firm).; Levy, Edward G.; Street and Smith Publications.;; American fiction |y 19th century.; American fiction |y 20th century.; Books.; Dime novels |v Periodicals.; Dime novels, American |v Illustrations.; Dime novels.; English fiction |y 19th century.; English fiction |y 20th Century.; Novels.; Paperbacks.; Penny Dreadfuls.; Romantic Fiction.; Women |x Fiction.
- Series I: Novels (Box 1-83)
  - Author: Abarbanell, J. R. Title: The rector's secret Series Number: 62 City: New York Publisher: J. S. Ogilvie Date: 1892 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Author: Abbott, Jacob Title: Josephine Series Title: Log Cabin Series Series Number: 45 City: New York Publisher: Log Cabin Press Date: undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Author: Adams, Mrs. Leith Title: Madelon Lemoine Series Title: Lippincott's Series of Select Novels Series Number: 77 City: Philadelphia Publisher: J. B. Lippincott Date: 1887 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Title: Adventures of Mr. Obadiah Oldbuck City: New York Publisher: Dick & Fitzgerald Date: undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Author: Aguilar, Grace Title: Home influence: a tale for mothers and daughters City: New York Publisher: Harper & Brothers Format: hard cover Date: 1855 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Author: Aiken, Albert W. Title: Joe Phenix private detective or the league of the skeleton keys Series Title: American Detective Series Series Number: 20 City: Cleveland Publisher: Arthur Westbrook Date: 1884 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Author: Aikin, George L. Title: Bob O'link; or, the boys of Chicago Series Title: The Lucky Series Series Number: 54 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1875 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Author: Aimard, Gustave Title: The adventurers, a story of a love chase Series Title: Lovell's Library Series Number: 560 City: New York Publisher: John W. Lovell Date: undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Author: Aimard, Gustave Title: The bee hunter, a tale Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 1742 City: New York Publisher: George Munro Date: 1891 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Author: Aimard, Gustave Title: The bee hunters, a tale of adventure Series Title: City: London Publisher: Ward, Lock, & Co. Date: undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Author: Albert, Mary Title: A hidden terror Series Title: Seaside Library City: New York Publisher: George Munro Date: 1887 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: At bay Series Title: The Sunset Series Series Number: 190 City: New York Publisher: J. S. Ogilvie Date: undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Beaton's bargain Series Title: The Arm Chair Library Series Number: 26 City: New York Publisher: F. M. Lupton Other Notes: 2 copies Date: 1893 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Beaton's bargain Series Title: The Empire Series Series Number: 218 City: New York Publisher: J. S. Ogilvie Other Notes: 2 copies Date: undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Brown, V.C. Series Title: Fenno's Select Series Series Number: 69 City: New York Publisher: R. F. Fenno & Company Date: 1900 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Brown, V.C. City: New York Publisher: R. F. Fenno & Company Format: hard cover Date: 1899 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: By woman's wit Series Title: American Series Series Number: 2 City: New York Publisher: M. J. Ivers & Co. Date: 1887 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: By woman's wit Series Title: Delphic Series Series Number: 16 City: New York Publisher: International Book Company Date: undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: A fight with fate Series Title: Lippincott's Select Novels Series Number: 208 City: Philadelphia Publisher: J. B. Lippincott Date: 1898 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Forging the fetters Series Title: The Electric Series Series Number: 10 City: New York Publisher: Butler Brothers Date: 1892 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Forging the fetters Series Title: Munro's Library of Popular Novels Series Number: 15 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1894 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Heart wins Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 1367 City: New York Publisher: George Munro Date: 1890 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Look before you leap Series Title: All Star Series Series Number: 37 City: Cleveland Publisher: Arthur Westbrook Date: undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Maid, wife or widow Series Title: The Sunset Series Series Number: 130 City: New York Publisher: J. S. Ogilvie Date: undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Maid, wife or widow? Series Title: The Advance Library Series Number: 40 City: Springfield, MA Publisher: Springfield Publishing Co. Date: 1892 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Mammon Series Title: Lovell's International Series Series Number: 219 City: New York Publisher: Lovell, Coryell & Company Date: 1891 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: A missing hero Series Title: Idle Hour Series Series Number: 8 City: New York Publisher: R. F. Fenno & Company Date: 1900 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Mona's choice Series Title: Chelsea Series Series Number: 107 City: New York Publisher: American Publishers Corporation Date: undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Ralph Wilton's weird Series Title: The Sunset Series Series Number: 219 City: New York Publisher: J. S. Ogilvie Date: undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: The secret of her life; or, Ralph Wilton's weird Series Title: Arrow Library Series Number: 317 City: New York Publisher: Street and Smith Date: 1904 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: The snare of the fowler City: New York Publisher: F. M. Lupton Format: hard cover Date: 1892 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Valerie's fate Series Title: Munro's Library of Popular Novels Series Number: 107 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1894 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: What gold cannot buy City: New York Publisher: F. M. Lupton Format: hard cover Date: undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: The wooing o't City: New York Publisher: Hurst and Company Format: hard cover Date: undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: The wooing o't Series Title: American Series Series Number: 268 City: New York Publisher: M. J. Ivers & Co. Date: 1891 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: The wooing o't Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 17 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1883 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: The wooing o't City: New York Publisher: Thomas Y. Crowell & Co. Format: hard cover Date: undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Author: Alexander, Mrs. Title: Zara, also maid, wife, or widow? Series Title: The Atlantic Library Series Number: 33 Date: undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Title: Alice; or, the adventures of an english girl in persia City: London Publisher: "Something to Read" Office Date: undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Author: Allen, Grant Title: The beckoning hand Series Title: The Hawthorne Library Series Number: 48 City: New York Publisher: Hurst and Company Date: 1900 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Author: Allen, Ida Reade Title: From tears to smiles or constant hearts Series Title: New Eagle Series Series Number: 1355 City: New York Publisher: Street and Smith Date: 1931 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Author: Allen, Ida Reade Title: The love that was her blessing Series Title: New Eagle Series Series Number: 1317 City: New York Publisher: Street and Smith Date: 1910 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Author: Allen, Ida Reade Title: Love, the tempter Series Title: New Eagle Series Series Number: 1017 City: New York Publisher: Street and Smith Date: 1892 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Author: Allen, Ida Reade Title: Norna's black fortune, or just a yankee girl Series Title: New Eagle Series Series Number: 1080 City: New York Publisher: Street and Smith Date: 1896 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Author: Allen, James Lane Title: The choir invisible City: New York Publisher: The Macmillan Company Format: hard cover Date: 1897 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Title: Almack's: a tale of english society City: New York Publisher: H. Long & Brother Date: 1855 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Author: Andrews, Lilian Herbert Title: Marie, a story of the morgue and catacombs of Paris Series Title: Once-A-Week Library Series Number: 24 City: New York Publisher: Peter Fenelon Collier Date: 1893 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Title: Angel or devil?, what the world thinks of woman Series Title: Minerva Series Series Number: 19 City: New York Publisher: The Minerva Publishing Company Date: 1890 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Author: Annesley, Miss M. Title: Light in the valley; or, the life and letters of Mrs. Hannah Bocking City: New York Publisher: Carlton & Porter Format: hard cover Date: 1860 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Author: Anthony, Geraldine Title: Four-in-hand, a story of smart life in New York and at a country club City: New York Publisher: D. Appleton and Company Format: hard cover Date: 1903 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Author: Anstey, F. Title: A fallen idol Series Title: Everyday Series City: New York Publisher: Syndicate Trading Company Date: undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Author: Anstey, F. Title: The pariah Series Title: Lippincott's Series of Select Novels Series Number: 102 City: Philadelphia Publisher: J. B. Lippincott Other Notes: 2 copies Date: 1889 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Author: Anstey, F. Title: The tinted venus, a farcical romance Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 503 City: New York Publisher: George Munro Date: 1885 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Author: Anstey, F. Title: Vice versa, or a lesson to fathers Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 59 City: New York Publisher: George Munro Date: 1883 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Author: Appleton, C. W. Title: A terrible legacy Series Title: Munro's Library Series Number: 769 City: New York Publisher: John W. Lovell Date: 1887 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Author: Appleton, Robert Title: Mrs. Harry St. John, a realistic novel of Boston fashionable life Series Title: Idylwild Series Series Number: 20 City: Chicago Publisher: Morrill, Higgins & Co Date: 1892 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Author: Ashmore, Annie Title: Faithful Margaret Series Title: Madison Square Series Series Number: 47 City: New York Publisher: G. W. Dillingham Date: 1889 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Author: Auerbach, Berthold Title: Joseph in the snow, a tale Series Title: Leisure Hour Series City: New York Publisher: Henry Holt and Company Format: hard cover Date: 1874 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Author: Austin, Mrs. Jane G. Title: The twelve great diamonds Series Title: The Bijou Series Series Number: 59 City: New York Publisher: F. M. Lupton Date: 1892 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Author: Ayres, Ruby M. Title: The highest bidder, a romance Series Title: Love Story Library Series Number: 9 City: New York Publisher: Street and Smith Date: undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Title: Baffled schemes Series Title: Library of Famous Fiction City: New York Publisher: R. Worthington Format: hard cover Date: 1867 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Author: Baker, Sir Samuel W. Title: Eight years' wanderings in Ceylon Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 533 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1885 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Author: Baker, Sir Samuel W., M.A., F.R.G.S. Title: The rifle and hound in Ceylon Series Title: Lovell's Library Series Number: 227 City: New York Publisher: John W. Lovell Date: 1883 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Author: Ballantyne, R. M. Title: Erling the bold Series Title: Munro's Library of Popular Novels Series Number: 69 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1894 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Author: Ballantyne, R. M. Title: Freaks on the fells; or, three months' rustication. and why I did not become a sailor City: Philadelphia Publisher: Porter & Coates Format: hard cover Date: undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Author: Balzac, Honore De Title: Eugenie Grandet Series Title: Ledger Library Series Number: 37 City: New York Publisher: Robert Bonner's Sons Date: 1891 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Author: Barbour, Maynard Title: That mainwaring affair City: London Publisher: Ward, Lock, & Co. Date: 1901 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Author: Baring-Gould, S. Title: Court royal, a story of cross currents Series Title: The Ideal Library Series Number: 171 City: Chicago Publisher: Donohue, Henneberry, & Co. Date: 1895 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Author: Barr, Mrs. Amelia E. Title: The last of the Macallisters Series Title: Lovell's Library Series Number: 1315 City: New York Publisher: John W. Lovell Date: 1888 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Author: Barr, Amelia E. Title: Mrs. Barr's short stories City: New York Publisher: Robert Bonner's Sons Date: 1892 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Author: Barrett, Frank Title: The great hesper Series Title: Arrow Library Series Number: 31 City: New York Publisher: Street and Smith Date: 1898 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Author: Barrett, Frank Title: His helpmate Series Title: The Souvenir Series Series Number: 66 City: New York Publisher: F. M. Lupton Date: 1892 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Author: Barrett, Frank Title: Kit Wyndham, or fettered for life Series Title: The Red Letter Series Series Number: 123 City: New York Publisher: National Publishing Co. Date: 1891 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Author: Barrett, Frank Title: Kit Wyndham, or fettered for life Series Title: The Fireside Series Series Number: 144 City: New York Publisher: International Book Company Date: 1892 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Author: Barrett, Frank Title: A smuggler's secret Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 1461 City: New York Publisher: George Munro Date: 1887 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Author: Barrie, J. M. Title: My lady nicotine Series Title: Globe Library Series Number: 156 City: Chicago and New York Publisher: Rand, McNally, & Co. Date: 1891 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Author: Barrie, James M. Title: When a man's single Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 2101 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1893 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Author: Barrie, J. M. Title: When a man's single, a tale of literary life City: New York Publisher: Hurst and Company Format: hard cover Date: undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Author: Barrie, James M. Title: A window in thrums Series Title: Munro's Library of Popular Novels Series Number: 154 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1895 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Title: The Barton experiment City: New York Publisher: G. P. Putnam's Sons Format: hard cover Date: 1877 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Author: Beach, Lewis Title: The goose hangs high, a play in three acts City: New York Publisher: Samuel French Date: [1923] (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Title: The beauty of the family Series Title: Happy Hour Stories Series Number: 236 City: London Publisher: "Family Herald" Press Date: undated (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Author: Bellamy, Edward Title: Looking backward, 2000-1887 Series Title: Ticknor's Paper Series Series Number: 38 City: Boston Publisher: Ticknor & Company Other Notes: c.1 Date: 1888 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Author: Bellamy, Edward Title: Looking backward, 2000-1887 Series Title: Ticknor's Paper Series Series Number: 38 City: Boston Publisher: Ticknor & Company Other Notes: c.2 Date: 1888 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Author: Belot, Adolphe Title: The woman of fire Series Title: Heart Series City: Chicago Publisher: Max Stein Date: 1908 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Author: Benedict, Frank Lee Title: Madame Series Title: Madison Square Series Series Number: 6 City: New York Publisher: G. W. Dillingham Date: 1886 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Author: Bennett, Emerson Title: Circumstantial evidence Series Title: The Arm Chair Library Series Number: 129 City: New York Publisher: F. M. Lupton Date: 1905 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Author: Benson, E. F. Title: Dodo Series Title: Munro's Library of Popular Novels Series Number: 4 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1894 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Author: Bentzon, Th. Title: Love's atonement, or expiation Series Title: The Bijou Series Series Number: 6 City: New York Publisher: F. M. Lupton Date: undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Author: Besant, Walter Title: All in a garden fair, the simple story of three boys and a girl Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: [97] City: New York Publisher: George Munro Date: 1887 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Author: Besant, Walter and James Rice Title: All sorts and conditions of men, an impossible story Series Title: American Series Series Number: 217 City: New York Publisher: M. J. Ivers & Co. Date: 1890 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Author: Besant, Walter Title: The holy rose Series Number: 128 City: Philadelphia Publisher: Royal Publishing Co. Date: undated (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Author: Besant, Walter Title: Love finds the way Series Title: The Handy Classic Series Series Number: 6 City: New York Publisher: Optimus Printing Company Date: undated (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Author: Besant, Walter and James Rice Title: They were married Series Title: Lovell's Library Series Number: 18 City: New York Publisher: John W. Lovell Date: 1883 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Author: Besant, Walter Title: Uncle Jack Series Title: Munro's Library of Popular Novels Series Number: 82 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1894 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Author: Betham-Edwards, M. Title: Forestalled, or the life quest Series Title: Lovell's International Series Series Number: 147 City: New York Publisher: John W. Lovell Date: 1891 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Author: Betham-Edwards, M. Title: The parting of the ways City: New York Publisher: John W. Lovell Date: 1890 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Author: Bisland, Elizabeth Title: A flying trip around the world City: New York Publisher: Harper & Brothers Format: hard cover Date: 1891 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Author: Black, William Title: A daughter of Heth City: New York Publisher: John W. Lovell Format: hard cover Date: undated (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Author: Black, William Title: In far Lochabar Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 1132 City: New York Publisher: George Munro Date: 1888 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Author: Black, William Title: Prince fortunatus Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 1268 City: New York Publisher: George Munro's Sons Date: 1888 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Author: Black, William Title: A princess of Thule City: New York Publisher: Harper & Brothers Format: hard cover Date: 1892 (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Author: Black, William Title: A princess of Thule City: Chicago, New York, and San Fransisco Publisher: Belford, Clarke, & Co. Format: hard cover Date: undated (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - Author: Black, William Title: A princess of Thule Series Title: The Favorite Library Series Number: 17 City: New York Publisher: The American News Company Date: undated (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Author: Black, William Title: That beautiful wretch, a Brighton story Series Title: Seaside Library Series Number: 49 City: New York Publisher: George Munro Date: 1883 (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - Author: Black, William Title: Yolande Series Title: Lovell's Library Series Number: 136 City: New York Publisher: John W. Lovell Date: 1883 (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Author: Blackford, Mrs. Title: The Scottish orphans, a moral tale; founded on an historical fact and calculated to improve the minds of young people City: New York Publisher: William Burgess Format: hard cover Date: 1832 (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Author: Blackmore, R. D. Title: Cristowell Series Title: Chelsea Series Series Number: 21 City: New York Publisher: American Publishers Corporation Date: undated (Box 6, Folder 108)